Guide to the George Plimpton Adams, Jr. and Evelyn Howell Yonker Adams papers, 1924-1977
Adams, George Plimpton Jr. and Evelyn Howell Yonker papers, 1924-1977
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Plimpton Adams, Jr. and Evelyn Howell Yonker Adams papers, 1924-1977
3942
George Plimpton Adams, Jr.
2.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notebooks, diaries, scrapbook.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, notebooks, diaries, and scrapbook of George Adams, and correspondence and diaries of Evelyn Adams.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, notebooks, diaries, and scrapbook of George Adams, and correspondence and diaries of Evelyn Adams.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Adams, George Plimpton, Jr., 1909-1977.; Adams, Evelyn Howell Yonker.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Scrapbooks.
Occupations:
College teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
George Adams
Box 1
Evelyn Adams
Box 2
Series II. Diaries
George Adams
Box 1,3,4
Evelyn Adams
Box 4
Series III. Notebooks and Scrapbooks
Boxes 1,5
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - George Adams
    - September, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - October-November, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - December, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - January-February, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - March-April, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - May, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - June-July, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - August-October, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - November-December, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - January-February, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - March-May, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - June-July, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - August-September, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - October-December, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - January-February, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - March-April, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - May-August, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1935-1974 (includes miscellaneous papers) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Evelyn Adams
    - 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - February-June, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - August-December, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1936, "Across Bythnia in a covered wagon", narrative with photographs. (From Marjorie McKillop?) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1945, includes letter from George S. Phylactopoulos-"Phi-Phi" - about occupation in Greece, 1940-1945. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1953-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II. Diaries
  - George Adams
    - Diaries
      - 1927-1929, 1934-1977 (Box 3)
      - 1924-1927 (Box 4)
    - Loose Material from Diaries
      - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1939-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1964-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Evelyn Adams
    - 1943,1944,1946-1951,1953-1958,1960-1973,1975,1977, Loose notebook pages, South American trip (Box 4)
- Series III. Notebooks and Scrapbooks
  - Notebook, Cambridge, 1927, Contains anecdotes, quotations, excerpts, poetry (Box 1)
  - Notebook, Undated, Contains anecdotes, quotations, excerpts, poetry (Box 1)
  - Notebook, Undated, Notes, quotations, excerpts, primarily on economics (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, Undated, Includes ship and restaurant menus (Box 5)